这里我们有一个熟悉的2link机器人，配置中Q2大于0。
Here we have our familiar 2link robot in the configuration where Q2 is greater than 0.
而且那就是具有相同末端执行器位置的机器人，但Q2现在更少了
And over laid on that is the robot with the same end effector position but Q2 is now less
这是这个机器人的两种可能的解决方案，以实现这一目标
than 0. These are the two possible solutions for this robot in order to achieve this particular
端点姿势。我们可能对机器人从一种配置移动到哪种配置感兴趣
endpoint pose. We might be interested in how the robot moves from one configuration to
另一个。对于机器人来说这是一个有趣的运动，因为终点位置是
the other. It's an interesting motion for the robot because the end point position is
完全相同，但关节角度Q1和Q2需要遵循一些有趣的轨迹
exactly the same but the joint angles Q1 and Q2 need to follow some interesting trajectory
从第一个配置移动到第二个配置。
to move from the first configuration to the second.
这是三个维度中更生动的例子。这显示了PUMA560机器人正在抓住
Here's a more vivid example in three dimensions. This shows a PUMA 560 robot moving to grab
一个球。现在我们可以看到机器人正在左手配置中掌握
a ball. Now we can see that the robot is making that grasp in either the left hand configuration
或右手配置。我们可能会问一个问题，“机器人是如何移动的
or the right handed configuration. We might ask the question, "How does the robot move
从左手配置到右手配置？我们如何计算
from a left handed configuration to a right handed configuration? How do we compute the
允许这种情况发生的轨迹？“
trajectory that allows that to happen?"
我们将再次为PUMA560机器人定义模型。将其加载到工作区中。
Once again we're going to define a model for our PUMA 560 robot. Load that into the workspace.
我们有机器人对象。在这里说工作区变量p560。我要定义一个姿势
We have the robot object. Say here. The workspace variable p560. I'm going to define a pose
我希望我的机器人能够采用。让我们通过这种同质化转变给他
that I'd like my robot to adopt. And let's give him by this homogeneous transformation
矩阵在这里。我将定义一个表示连接角度集的新工作空间变量
matrix here. I'm going to define a new workspace variable that represents the set of join angles
机器人要求在左手配置中采用这种特殊姿势。我用
required by the robot to adopt this particular pose in the left handed configuration. I use
ikine6s方法，传递表示所需姿势的均匀变换
the ikine6s method, pass in the homogeneous transformation representing the desired pose
并且开关L指示机器人将处于左手配置和此状态
and the switch L to indicate the robot is to be in a left handed configuration and this
是所需的关节角度集合。我可以为右手配置做同样的事情。
is the required set of joint angles. I can do the same thing for a right handed configuration.
我将为一个名为QR的变量创建一个新工作区。
I'm going to create a new workspace for a variable called QR.
我们来看看这些特殊的机器人配置。我可以绘制配置
Let's have a look at these particular robot configurations. I can plot the configuration
QL。它在棒图表示中看起来像这样。让我从一个看看
QL. And it looks like this in stick figure representation. Let me look at that from a
不同的有利位置。对于右手配置，它看起来像这样。现在
different vantage point. And it looks like this for the right handed configuration. Now
比我们自己领先一点，我要做的就是创造一条轨迹
getting a little bit ahead of ourselves, what I'm going to do is to create a trajectory
并显示机器人从所有关节角度相等的配置移动
and show the robot moving from the configuration where all those joint angles are equal to
0到左手姿势。这将在50个时间步骤中完成。
0 to the left handed pose. It's going to do that in 50 time steps.
现在是jtraj函数的结果，我们将在后面的讲座中详细讨论这个问题
Now the result of the jtraj function and we'll talk more about this later in the lecture
是一个包含50行和6列的矩阵。每行对应于特定的时间步长。行
is a matrix with 50 rows and 6 columns. Each row corresponds to particular time step. Row
1是轨迹的第一点。第50行是轨迹的最后一点。每
1 is the first point of the trajectory. Row 50 is the last point of the trajectory. Each
列表示特定的关节角度。
column represents a particular joint angle.
现在，机器人工具箱可以轻松处理轨迹。所以我绘制而不是特定的
Now the robotic tool box can easily deal with trajectories. So I plot but instead of a particular
关节角度我绘制一个轨迹。我们看到机器人现在从0角配置移动
joint angle I plot a trajectory. We see the robot now moving from 0 angle configuration
左手配置。
to a left handed configuration.
我可以改变这两个，从0角度配置移动
I can change this two, move from the 0 angle configuration
右手配置，我可以再次绘制。看机器人在做什么
to the right handed configuration, and once again I can plot that. See the robot doing
一个非常复杂的动作。最后我能做的就是展示机器人从哪里移动
a quite convoluted looking motion. Finally what I can do is show the robot moving from
左手配置到右手配置。
the left handed configuration to the right handed configuration.
这是一个有趣的动作，因为机器人开始和结束轨迹
And this is an interesting motion because the robot starts and ends the trajectory with
它的末端效应器具有完全相同的姿势。但在机器人之间将会经历
its end effector in exactly the same pose. But in between the robot is going to go through
一些扭曲，以便从左撇子机器人变为右撇子机器人。
some contortions in order to change from being a left handed robot to a right handed robot.
计算轨迹，然后我们将看一下。有趣的是看
Compute the trajectory and then we're going to have a look at that. Interesting to see
机器人在这做什么。您可以看到动作非常复杂，末端效应器结束
what the robot does here. You can see that the motion is quite complex and the end effector ends
就在它开始的地方。有时在制造场景中，机器人确实需要改变
up just where it started. Sometimes in a manufacturing scenario, the robot does exactly need to change
从左撇子到右撇子。也许它需要访问对象
from being left handed to being right handed. Perhaps it needs to access objects at the
其工作空间的极端和需要改变配置。
extreme ends of its workspace and needs to change configuration.
因此，这些配置改变运动，机器人的所有运动都没有网络
So these configuration change motions, there is no net over all the motion of the robot
但是当它正在进行配置更改时，可能会有一些非常狂野和令人兴奋的事情
but while it's doing the configuration change, there can be some quite wild and exciting
联合议案。当你指挥这样的动作时，你需要有点小心
joint motions. You need to be a little bit careful when you command such a motion that
机器人不会在其工作空间中碰撞任何东西。
the robot is not going to collide with anything in its workspace.